<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD XHTML 1.0 Transitional//EN"
    "http://www.w3.org/TR/xhtml1/DTD/xhtml1-transitional.dtd">

<html xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<head>
	<meta content="text/html; charset=us-ascii" http-equiv="content-type" />
	<title>EC-Admin Plugin</title>
    <link rel="stylesheet" href= "../../plugins/@PLUGIN_NAME@/pluginhelp.css" type="text/css" media= "screen" />
</head>

<body>
    <div class="help">
		<h1>EC-Admin</h1>
<p>Plugin Version @PLUGIN_VERSION@</p>
    	<hr style="margin-left: -10px; margin-top: 10px; height: 1px; width: 100%; color: #5981BD;" noshade="noshade" />

        <p>EC-Admin is a collection of administrative procedures to help you
manage your server. Its inception was sparked by requests from customers
during my Professional Services engagements. It has grown over the years to
what it is now.</p>

		<p>It contains the following modules:</p>
		<ul>
			<li><a href="#look">Look and Feel</a></li>
			<li><a href="#jobs">Jobs and Workspaces management</a></li>
			<li><a href="#plugin">Plugins</a></li>
			<li><a href="#artifacts">Artifacts management</a></li>
			<li><a href="#backup">Object export and backup</a></li>
			<li><a href="#semaphore">Semaphore management</a></li>
			<li><a href="#perf">Performance metrics</a></li>
			<li><a href="#license">License Logger</a></li>
			<li><a href="#postp">postp debugger helper</a></li>
		</ul>

		<h2><a name="installation"></a>Installation</h2>
		
        <p>This collection of procedures can be found on our 
        	<a href="https://github.com/electriccommunity/EC-Admin">GitHub
        		repository</a>. It is available as a plugin delivered 
        	in the form of a .jar file or you can simply get the source code 
        	and recompile it yourself.</p>

		<p>To install the plugin, use the "Install from File/URL" tab in the
			administration/Plugins or use the "installPlugin" API.</p>
 
		<p>To install on 4.0.x or or 4.1.x, import the EC_4.0.xml file. Be 
			aware that some features are not present as the original project 
			makes use of createJobStep() API which was introduced in 4.2.0:<br/>
ectool import /path_to/EC-Admin_for_EC_4.0.xml --disableSchedules 1</p>

		<p>If you get an error with the passKey, use the "--force 1" option</p>

    <p>
        IMPORTANT: For all parameter descriptions below, required
        parameters are shown in <span class="required">bold
        italics</span>.
    </p>

		<h1><a name="look"></a>Look and Feel</h1>
		<h2>changeBannerColor</h2>
		<p>If you work on multiple Commander servers like a development and a 
			production instances, this procedure is for you. It allows you to change 
			the color of the top banner and the logo to make it easier to identify your different 
			servers. Feel free 
			to <a href="mailto:lrochette@electric-cloud.com">send me</a> new ones if 
			you have a more artistic touch than me. Or better
			push your changes to 
			<a href="https://github.com/electriccommunity/EC-Admin">GitHub</a>.</p>

		    <table class="grid">
		        <thead>
		            <tr>
		                <th>Parameter</th>
		                <th>Description</th>
		            </tr>
		        </thead>

		        <tbody>
		            <tr>
		                <td class='required'>color</td>
		                <td>Choose a color for your top banner</td>
		            </tr>
		            <tr>
		                <td>logo</td>
		                <td>Choose a set of pre-rendered logo to indicate 
				if you server is of type DEV, SDK, TEST or PROD, in black or white to  
				go along different background colors.</td>
		            </tr>
		            <tr>
		                <td>logoFile</td>
		                <td>The path on the Commander server to upload your own logo. If this value is not blank it will overwritten the logo parameter above.</td>
		            </tr>
		            <tr>
		                <td>webResource</td>
		                <td>The name of the resource running on your webserver to allow the copy of the logo and banner color files.</td>
		            </tr>
		        </tbody>
		    </table>
			<img src="../../plugins/@PLUGIN_KEY@/images/help/changeBannerColor.png" 
				 alt="changeBannerColor parameters" />
			<p>will produce</p>
			<img src="../../plugins/@PLUGIN_KEY@/images/help/RedDev.png" 
				 alt="Red DEV example" />


		<h1><a name="jobs"></a>Jobs and Workspaces management</h1>
		<p>This set of procedures will help you manage your old jobs and the 
			associated workspaces.</p>

			<h2>jobsCleanup:</h2> 
			<p>A procedure to delete jobs older than a specified number of
days. It will also delete associated workspace job directories.</p>

		    <table class="grid">
		        <thead>
		            <tr>
		                <th>Parameter</th>
		                <th>Description</th>
		            </tr>
		        </thead>

		        <tbody>
		            <tr>
		                <td class='required'>olderThan</td>
		                <td>Indicate the number of days after which jobs are deleted</td>
		            </tr>
		            <tr>
		                <td class='required'>jobType</td>
		                <td>Define what jobs should be deleted: Error, Warning or all.</td>
		            </tr>
		            <tr>
		                <td>jobProperty</td>
		                <td>Name of a property attached to your jobs. If this property is set, your job won't be deleted no matter how old it is.</td>
		            </tr>
		            <tr>
		                <td>jobPatternMatching</td>
		                <td>A SQL pattern matching to automatically preserve some jobs. The pattern must solve for a LIKE statement.</td>
		            </tr>
		            <tr>
		                <td class='required'>delete</td>
		                <td>If this option is not set, only report is done. No real data are deleted</td>
		            </tr>
		            <tr>
		                <td class='required'>computeUsage</td>
		                <td>Check off to skip the computation of the number of steps and the file space used for the job. This will speed up the execution.</td>
		            </tr>
		        </tbody>
		    </table>

			<img src="../../plugins/@PLUGIN_KEY@/images/help/jobsCleanup.png" 
				 alt="jobsCleanup parameters" />

			<h2>jobCleanup_byResult:</h2> 
            <p>A procedure to delete jobs older than a specified number of days.
It will also delete associated workspace job directories. It will keep the
number of successful, failed and warning jobs you entered. You can also
provide a property name, if this property is attached to the job, it won't be
deleted no matter how old. A report only mode prevents any real deletion.</p>

			<h2>deleteWorksapceOrphans:</h2> 

            <p>A procedure to crawl a workspace directory to find orphan jobs
(directories without a matching job) on a specified resource.</p>

			<h2>deleteObjects:</h2> 
            <p>A procedure to quickly delete jobs or workflows older than a
specified number of days. It will <b>not</b> delete associated workspace job
directories. This is for customers with huge job or workflow database.</p>


		<h1><a name="plugin"></a>Plugins</h1>
		<h2>Plugin Synchronization</h2>
		<p>This procedure synchronizes plugins between the server and 
		a resource. Plugins are uploaded first as artifacts if it has not been 
		done already and then downloaded on the resource if it does not 
		already exist in the plugins directory.</p>
		
		<h2>Plugin creation</h2>
		<h3>createPluginFromProject</h3>
		<p><b>Note:</b> This procedure requires access to the jar or zip 
			executable in the PATH.</p>
		<p>The procedure "createPluginFromProject" allows the transformation of a 
			project into a plugin. The parameters are the following:</p>
		    <table class="grid">
		        <thead>
		            <tr>
		                <th>Parameter</th>
		                <th>Description</th>
		            </tr>
		        </thead>

		        <tbody>
					<tr>
			        	<td class='required'>Project</td>
						<td>The name of the project to transform into a plugin</td>
		            </tr>
					<tr>
			        	<td>Plugin</td>
						<td>The name of the plugin. If left empty, it will default to
					the project name.</td>
		            </tr>
					<tr>
			        	<td>Category</td>
						<td>The category of the plugin. It helps filter the plugin list in
					the Plugins page and in the picker list.</td>
		            </tr>
					<tr>
			        	<td  class='required'>Version</td>
						<td>Version of the plugin to create. A build number is automatically 
							added (after incrementation) to ensure uniq version numbers.</td>
		            </tr>
					<tr>
			        	<td>Description</td>
						<td>The description of the plugin to display in the main 
						plugin page. If left empty it will default to the 
						description of the project.</td>
		            </tr>
					<tr>
			        	<td>Author</td>
						<td>Name of he author of the project to transform into a plugin.</td>
		            </tr>
					<tr>
			        	<td>Email</td>
						<td>The email of the author.</td>
		            </tr>
					<tr>
			        	<td>Comment</td>
						<td>if this parameter is not empty, it will be added to the CHANGELOG for traceability.</td>
		            </tr>
					<tr>
			        	<td>fixSelfReferences</td>
						<td>Replace self references to the project in sub-prceodure calls by an empty string to be sure the plugins= created will not call the original project instead of itself.</td>
		            </tr>
					<tr>
			        	<td>createArtifact</td>
						<td>Save the new created plugin as an artifact version.</td>
		            </tr>
					<tr>
			        	<td>installPlugin</td>
						<td>A Boolean to install or not the plugin after creation</td>
		            </tr>
					<tr>
			        	<td>promotePlugin</td>
						<td>A Boolean to promote or not the plugin after installation</td>
		            </tr>
					<tr>
			        	<td>moveJobs</td>
						<td>A Boolean to move or not jobs from the previous 
							version into the current one upon promotion.</td>
		            </tr>
		        </tbody>
		    </table>

			<img src="../../plugins/@PLUGIN_KEY@/images/help/createPluginFromProject.png" 
				 alt="createPluginFromProject parameters" />

		<p>At the project level, you can define the following properties to 
			alter the behavior of the plugin creation:</p>
			<dl>
				<dt><b>ec_visibility:</b></dt>
				<dd>Choose <b>all</b> to have the plugin shows in the project 
					list (like EC-Admin), or <b>pickListOnly</b> (default) to 
					have your procedures available only through the plugin 
					procedure picker (when you choose plugin as a step).</dd>
				<dt><b>help:</b></dt>
				<dd>This property allows you to create a Help page associated 
					with your plugin. The page you are currently reading is 
					created this way so feel free to explore the help property
					 in the EC-Admin plugin/project for an example.</dd>
				<dt><b>promoteAction</b></dt>
				<dd>This property would contain some Perl code to take action
					when the plugin change state. Look at the ec_setup property
					in the plugins installed on your system to get a better idea
					of what you can accomplish.<br/>
					For example to set a property hwne the plugin is pomoted 
					you could add the the following code to the promoteAction
					procedure:<br/>
					<pre><code>
if ( $promoteAction eq 'promote' ) {
    $batch->setProperty( "/projects/$pluginName/addedByPromote", "123" );
}
					</code></pre>
				</dd>
			</dl>
		<p>In addition each procedure can modify the behavior with the 
			following 2 properties:</p>
			<dl>
				<dt><b>exposeToPlugin:</b></dt>
				<dd>This property if set to 1 will add the procedure to 
					ec_setup to be shown in the procedure picker list when 
					choosing a plugin step.</dd>
				<dt><b>descriptionForPlugin:</b></dt>
				<dd>This property will be shown as the description in the 
					picker list mentioned above. If it's empty or non-existent,
					 the description will be description of the procedure 
					 itself.</dd>
			</dl>

		<h3>projectAsCode</h3>

		<p><b>Note:</b> This procedure requires access to a resource with the 
			Commander SDK installed.</p>

		<p>This procedure is an extension of createPluginFromProject. It also
		creates a plugin but instead of simply exporting the project, it
		"explodes" each step in its own file for finer granularity check in
		in your favorite SCM tool.<br/>
		All the properties associated with createPluginFromProject still apply.</p>

		    <table class="grid">
		        <thead>
		            <tr>
		                <th>Parameter</th>
		                <th>Description</th>
		            </tr>
		        </thead>

		        <tbody>
					<tr>
			        	<td class='required'>Project</td>
						<td>The name of the project to transform into a plugin</td>
		            </tr>
					<tr>
			        	<td>Plugin</td>
						<td>The name of the plugin. If left empty, it will default to
					the project name.</td>
		            </tr>
					<tr>
			        	<td>Category</td>
						<td>The category of the plugin. It helps filter the plugin list in
					the Plugins page and in the picker list.</td>
		            </tr>
					<tr>
			        	<td  class='required'>Version</td>
						<td>Version of the plugin to create. A build number is automatically 
							added (after incrementation) to ensure uniq version numbers.</td>
		            </tr>
					<tr>
			        	<td>Description</td>
						<td>The description of the plugin to display in the main 
						plugin page. If left empty it will default to the 
						description of the project.</td>
		            </tr>
					<tr>
			        	<td>Author</td>
						<td>Name of he author of the project to transform into a plugin.</td>
		            </tr>
					<tr>
			        	<td>Email</td>
						<td>The email of the author.</td>
		            </tr>
					<tr>
			        	<td>Comment</td>
						<td>if this parameter is not empty, it will be added to the CHANGELOG for traceabiity.</td>
		            </tr>
					<tr>
			        	<td>Directory</td>
						<td>The name of the directory where to create the complete file structure. Typically a directory you will check in in your SCM.</td>
		            </tr>
					<tr>
			        	<td>SDK resource</td>
						<td>The name of an agent where the Commander SDK is installed. Required to build the plugin.</td>
		            </tr>
					<tr>
			        	<td>SDK Location</td>
						<td>The path where the Commander SDK is installed on the above resources..</td>
		            </tr>
					<tr>
			        	<td>fixSelfReferences</td>
						<td>Replace self references to the project in sub-prceodure calls by an empty string to be sure the plugins= created will not call the original project instead of itself.</td>
		            </tr>
					<tr>
			        	<td>overwrite</td>
						<td>if the ec_setup.pl already exists, it is not overwritten. Check this parameter overwrite with a content dynamically generated based on project properties.</td>
		            </tr>
					<tr>
			        	<td>disableCleanup</td>
						<td>Prevents the exported project file to be deleted. It can be an issue when  the agent and server run as different users.</td>
		            </tr>		            
					<tr>
			        	<td>projectAsCode</td>
						<td>Include a bit of code to revert the plugin to a 
							project upon promotion if this option is checked.</td>
		            </tr>
					<tr>
			        	<td>createArtifact</td>
						<td>Save the new created plugin as an artifact version.</td>
		            </tr>
					<tr>
			        	<td>installPlugin</td>
						<td>A Boolean to install or not the plugin after creation</td>
		            </tr>
					<tr>
			        	<td>promotePlugin</td>
						<td>A Boolean to promote or not the plugin after installation</td>
		            </tr>
					<tr>
			        	<td>moveJobs</td>
						<td>A Boolean to move or not jobs from the previous 
							version into the current one upon promotion.</td>
		            </tr>
		        </tbody>
		    </table>

			<img src="../../plugins/@PLUGIN_KEY@/images/help/projectAsCode.png" 
				 alt="projectAsCode parameters" />

		<p>At the project level, you can define the addtional following properties to alter the behavior of the plugin creation:</p>
			<dl>
				<dt><b>configureCredentials:</b></dt>
				<dd>this property will indicate to EC-Admin to code to help create configuration to manage credentials for your plugin. It adds:
					<ul>
						<li>A procedure name "createConfiguration". You need to modify the code of the step "createAndAttachCredential" in order to reference your own procedures and steps where you want to attach those credentials.</li>
						<li>Some cgi-bin scripts.</li>
						<li>Some java code to manage the different UI to create, edit and delete configurations.</li>
						<li>A "configure" link for your plugin on the pluginManager page.</li>
					</ul>
				Once the procedures and steps have been created, they will not be overwritten so it's safe to modify them to acoomodate your own needs.
				</dd>

				<dt><b>filesToCopy:</b></dt>
				<dd>This property will indicate to the ant plugin builder to add files and directories to your jar file. It will create an entry for the filesToCopy.extras in your build.xml. For example, EC-Admin includes lib/*.jar that is used to manage the configurations required for the credentials.</dd>
			</dl>

		<p><b>Note:</b> EC-Admin is released on 
		<a href="https://github.com/electriccommunity/EC-Admin">GitHub</a> using 
		this procedure.</p>

		<h1><a name="artifacts"></a>Artifact Management</h1>
		
		<h2>artifactRepositorySynchronization</h2>

		<p>Synchronize the content of remote artifact repositories to a local
		resource. You can use pattern matching to select specific artifact
		versions to synchronize.</p>

		<h2>artifactsCleanup</h2> 
		
		<p>A procedure to delete artifact versions older than a specified number
of days. Same as for jobs above, a property allows preventing the deletion. Once the
artifacts have been deleted, artifact repositories and artifact caches are
cleaned as well (deleting stale artifacts).  A report mode prevents any
real deletion.</p>

		<h2>artifactsCleanup_byQuantity</h2>

		<p>As "ArtifactsCleanup"", this procedure deletes artifact versions 
			older than a specified number
of days but keeps only X per Artifact. Again, a property allows preventing the 
deletion. Once the
artifacts have been deleted, artifact repositories and artifact caches are
cleaned as well (deleting stale artifacts).  A report only mode prevents any
real deletion.</p>

		<h1><a name="backup"></a>Object export and backup</h1>

        <p>This set of procedures is to help you export objects from
ElectricCommander for a potential inclusion into your SCM for
versioning.</p>
		
		<h2>saveProjects</h2>

        <p>This procedure simply exports your projects in a directory on the
server. It is recommended to enable the nightly schedule associated
with it to backup your projects on a regular basis.</p>

		<h2>saveAllObjects</h2>

        <p>This procedure brings a finer granularity to a full server export.
For  example, it may be easier to retrieve a simple project or procedure
instead of the full server export or database backup to undo r a wrong action
or a bad code change. By  default it exports projects and each procedure
individually. In addition by  enabling the matching checkboxes, you can also
export resources,  resource pools, workspaces, users and groups, and with 5.x
and later ElectricFlow Deploy objects (Applications, Components and
Environments). It is recommended to enable the nightly schedule associated
with it to backup your projects on a regular basis.</p>

		<p><b>Note:</b> Use saveProjects or saveAllObjects depending on the
		granularity you are requiring.</p>

		<h1><a name="semaphore"></a>Semaphore Management</h1>

		<h2>acquireSemaphore and releaseSemaphore:</h2>
			
		<p>Those 2 procedures are used to create a 
gate for a set of steps. The important part is to use a resource with a step 
limit of one to ensure the atomicity of increasing and decreasing the gate 
value.</p>

		<h1><a name="perf"></a>Performance metrics</h1>
		<p>This procedure returns some information about your 
			ElectricCommander server like number of processors, total RAM, 
			available RAM, 
ping times with agents, relative performance of agents, ... 
In addition it checks the amount of time spent running steps on the server 
local agents as this should be minimized as much as possible.</p>

		<h1><a name="license"></a>License Logger</h1>
		<p>The License Logger mechanism is intended to collect and email various
license-related statistics. It is implemented as a set of schedules and procedures,
along with a set of configuration properties.</p>
		<p>The configuration properties are located under /server/EC-Admin/licenseLogger/config.
The property sheet is created upon promotion if it does not already exists.The following 
properties can be set up:</p>

		    <table class="grid">
		        <thead>
		            <tr>
		                <th>Property</th>
		                <th>Description</th>
		            </tr>
		        </thead>

		        <tbody>
					<tr>
			        	<td>resource</td>
						<td>The name of the resource on which to run the procedures. Default is "local".</td>
		            </tr>
					<tr>
			        	<td>workspace</td>
						<td>The name of the workspace used by the procedures. Default is "default".</td>
		            </tr>
					<tr>
			        	<td>cleanOldJobs</td>
						<td>A boolean to remove old jobs so only the last one is kept for each procedure. It keeps your job history cleaner.</td>
		            </tr>
					<tr>
			        	<td class='required'>emailConfig</td>
						<td>The name of the mail configuration used to send report.</td>
		            </tr>
					<tr>
			        	<td class='required'>emailTo</td>
						<td>The list of recipients (semicolon separated) to which to send the reports.</td>
		            </tr>
            	</tbody>
        	</table>

		<h1><a name="postp"></a>postp debugger helper</h1>
		<p>The debugPostp is a simple procedure to help you debug with postp. Traditionally you would call postp from the command line with the jobStepId of the faulty postp and adding some additional option to see details. This new procedure does that for you on Linux and Windows, you just have to pass the jobStepId as a parameter.</p>

		<h1>Contact authors</h1> 
		<dl>
			<dt>License Logger</dt>
			<dd>Mike Westerhof (<a href="mailto:mwesterhof@electric-cloud.com">mwesterhof@electric-cloud.com</a>)</dd>
			<dt>deleteObjects</dt>
			<dd>Tanay Nagjee (<a href="mailto:tanay@electric-cloud.com">tanay@electric-cloud.com</a>)</dd>
  			<dt>Other</dt>
  			<dd>Laurent Rochette (<a href="mailto:lrochette@electric-cloud.com">lrochette@electric-cloud.com</a>)</dd>
		</dl>

	<h1>Legal Jumbo</h1>
 
	<p>This module is free for use. Modify it however you see fit to better your 
experience using ElectricCommander. Share your enhancements and fixes.</p>

	<p>This module is not officially supported by Electric Cloud. It has undergone no 
formal testing and you may run into issues that have not been uncovered in the 
limited manual testing done so far.</p>

	<p>Electric Cloud should not be held liable for any repercussions of using this 
software.</p>
	</div>
</body>
</html>
